Guide to the Veteran Feminists of America Records, 1972-2017 RL.01331
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Veteran Feminists of America records
1971-2017
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Veteran Feminists of America
RL.01331
30.4 Linear Feet
Veteran Feminists of America (VFA) is a nonprofit organization for veterans of the Second Wave of the feminist movement. It was founded by Jacqueline Ceballos and held its first feminist reunion in 1993. The organization continues to operate today, sponsoring reunions, programs, and publications honoring feminists throughout the United States. The accession (2008-0286) includes administrative files, program and reunion materials, obituaries, correspondence, financial information, newsletters, periodicals, and photographs relating to the activities and programs of the Veteran Feminists of America. Special media formats include DVDs, floppy disks, and CDs, some of which have been withdrawn for electronic preservation. There are also medals and other ephemera. The addition (2008-0254) consists of DVDs of VFA events and interviews. Addition (2009-0131) includes administrative files, events files, and other organizational information. Addition (2010-0097) includes program information and other organizational files, predominately from VFA's conference, The Gender Agenda: Beyond Borders, held in Dallas in March 2010. Addition (2010-0128) includes honoree information forms and materials from the Dallas conference. Addition (2012-0083) includes a program from the Tribute to Helen Reddy event (2006) and two copies of an associated commerically-available music compact disc by Sandy Rapp; along with the souvenir program from the VFA salute to feminist lawyers (2009). Addition (2017-0058) includes conference programs from several conferences that took place in the early 2000's and 2010's. The addition also includes meeting minutes from the annual VFA board meeting. Addition (2017-0139) includes administrative files and planning materials for different events that documented the history of VFA and the Second Wave Feminist Movement; along with a history of VFA (2013). Acquired by the Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture.
30.4 lin. ft.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
Purchase, 2008 (2008-0286), 25.1 lin. ft.
Purchase, 2008 (2008-0254), 1.2 lin. ft.
Gift, 2009 (2009-0131), 1.8 lin. ft.
Gift, 2010 (2010-0097), 0.6 lin. ft.
Gift, 2010 (2010-0128), 0.6 lin. ft.
Gift, 2008 (2012-0083), 0.1 lin. ft.
Gift, 2014 (2015-0069), 2.0 lin. ft.
Gift, 2017 (2017-0058), .2 lin. ft.
Gift, 2017 (2017-0139), .2 lin. ft.
Biographical / Historical Note
Veteran Feminists of America (VFA) is a nonprofit organization for veterans of the Second Wave of the feminist movement. It was founded by Jacqueline Ceballos and held its first feminist reunion in 1993. The organization continues to operate today, sponsoring reunions, programs, and publications honoring feminists throughout the United States.
Collection Overview
The collection (2008-0286) includes administrative files, program and reunion materials, obituaries, correspondence, financial information, newsletters, periodicals, and photographs relating to the activities and programs of the Veteran Feminists of America. Special media formats include DVDs, floppy disks, and CDs, some of which have been withdrawn for electronic preservation. There are also medals and other ephemera. Acquired as part of the Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture.
The addition (2008-0254) (64 items; 1.2 lin. ft.) consists of DVDs of VFA events and interviews.
The addition (2009-0131) (900 items; 1.8 lin. ft., dated 2001-2008) consists of board minutes, administrative materials, program files, some correspondence, and publicity. Program files include reunions, special presentations, conferences on feminist history and issues, and other educational and commemorative events. In particular, the accession includes materials from the Salute to Feminist Lawyers event put on in June 2008 at the Harvard Club in New York.
The addition (2010-0097) (300 items; 0.6 lin. ft., dated 2005-2010) includes miscellaneous newsletters, dated 2005-2008; board meeting minutes from 2007; event and program files from a 2009 Pompano Beach, FL awards gala and a Dallas conference entitled The Gender Agenda: Beyond Borders, held March 2010. The Dallas event files include copies of materials on 22 honorees, as well as the program text and other promotional materials. Other topics in this accession include website initiatives and the Feminists Who Changed America book launch.
The addition (2010-0128) (150 items; 0.6 lin. ft., dated 2009-2010) includes materials submitted by honorees at the The Gender Agenda: Beyond Borders conference held by the VFA in Dallas. Materials include information forms, resumes, essays, and other miscellaneous biographies.
The addition (2012-0083) (4 items; 0.1 lin. ft., dated 2006, 2009) includes a program from the Tribute to Helen Reddy event (2006) and two copies of an associated commerically-available music compact disc by Sandy Rapp; along with the souvenir program from the VFA salute to feminist lawyers (2009).
The addition (2015-0069) (1800 items; 3.0 lin. ft., dated 2011-2014) consists of event information, program and administrative files relating to the activities of the Veteran Feminists of America. Special media formats include DVDs of event programming, including the Kate Millett festival (2012), and Labor and the Women's Movement (2014).
The addition (2017-0058) (.2 lin. ft., dated 2002-2017) consists of program and administrative files related to the operation of the Veteran Feminists of America. Special media includes two DVDs; one is of the Harvard Club Luncheon (2014) and the other is of the Veteran Feminist Association South Florida Luncheon (2009).
The addition (2017-0139) (.2 lin. ft., dated 2007-2017 consists of administrative and program files related to the activities of the Veteran Feminists of America.
Acquired as part of the Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture.
Photographs; DVDs; Compact discs; Abortion; Equal rights amendments -- United States; Feminism -- United States; Floppy disks; Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture; Abzug, Bella S., 1920-1998; Ceballos, Jacqueline; East, Catherine; National Organization for Women; Millett, Kate; Reddy, Helen; Steinem, Gloria; Veteran Feminists of America
- Accession (2008-0286), 1972-2008, 18 boxes
  Scope and Contents note
  The accession (2008-0286) includes administrative files, program and reunion materials, obituaries, correspondence, financial information, newsletters, periodicals, and photographs relating to the activities and programs of the Veteran Feminists of America. Special media formats include DVDs, floppy disks, and CDs, some of which have been withdrawn for electronic preservation. There are also medals and other ephemera. Acquired as part of the Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture.
  - Newsletters, 1992-2008, 24 folders (Box 1)
  - Checkbook registers, 1 folder (Box 1)
  - Financial information, 1995-2003, 22 folders (Box 1)
  - Foam mounted book covers (Box 1)
  - 4 coffee mugs: Bella, Gloria, Kate, Betty (Box 2)
  - Chicago, 2004 (Box 2)
  - Website, 2004 (Box 2)
  - Joanne Kantrowitz, 2004 (Box 2)
  - Committees, 2004 (Box 2)
  - Seneca Falls, 2005 (Box 2)
  - Betty Newcomb, 2005 (Box 2)
  - Ali G, Borat, 2005 (Box 2)
  - 2005 (Box 2)
  - Dell event, 2005 (Box 2)
  - 2005 Feb. (Box 2)
  - 2006 (Box 2)
  - NOW Albany Conference, 2006 (Box 2)
  - Ali G, Borat, 2006 (Box 2)
  - Betty, 2006 (Box 2)
  - Betty's death, 2006 (Box 2)
  - Betty memorials, emails (Box 2)
  - Reddy press, programs (Box 2)
  - 2006 Aug. 26, 3 folders (Box 2)
  - WR/HR (Box 2)
  - Kate's eulogy (Box 2)
  - First Mothers, 2006 (Box 2)
  - Tickets, seats, 2006 (Box 2)
  - Barbara's talk, 2006 (Box 2)
  - More, 2006 (Box 2)
  - NYC, 2006 (Box 2)
  - Misc., 2006 (Box 2)
  - PR FWCA (Box 2)
  - Muriel's Preplanning, 2006 (Box 2)
  - After Nov. 13 (Box 2)
  - 2006 Dec. (Box 2)
  - Florida, 2006 (Box 2)
  - Florida board meeting, 2006 (Box 3)
  - General emails, 2006 (Box 3)
  - Newsletters, 2006 Jan.-April (Box 3)
  - VFA Board (Box 3)
  - Gilmore's mail (Box 3)
  - 2006 Mar.-April (Box 3)
  - American Biological interview, 2006 (Box 3)
  - Women's Demo Club, 2006 (Box 3)
  - Organizations for August, 2006 (Box 3)
  - Los Angeles, 2006 May, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Karen DeCrow (Box 3)
  - LA Caterer, 2006 (Box 3)
  - Helen Reddy program, 2006 May (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous, 2003 (Box 3)
  - Expo, 2000 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 2000 (Box 3)
  - 2003 (Box 3)
  - Barbara Love, Feminists who changed America, 1998 (Box 3)
  - Susan B. Anthony Center (Box 3)
  - Publications, 1980-2005, 9 magazines
    - Lilith (Box 3)
    - Ms. Magazine (Box 3)
    - On the Issues (Box 3)
  - D.C., 2000 Apr. (Box 3)
  - Kappie Spencer (Box 3)
  - Karline Tierney (Box 3)
  - Caterers, 2000 Apr. (Box 3)
  - D.C. event notes, 2000 (Box 3)
  - D.C. tickets sold, 2000 (Box 3)
  - D.C. press, 2000 (Box 3)
  - Invitations sent, 2000 (Box 3)
  - La. Transcripts, 2001 Mar. (Box 3)
  - Louisiana, 2001 (Box 3)
  - Isadora evening, 2002 Apr. (Box 3)
  - Guests, final count (Box 3)
  - Writers names, 2002 (Box 3)
  - Writers, 2002 (Box 3)
  - Title IX Conference, 2002 (Box 3)
  - Bios and letters, Title IX, 2002 (Box 3)
  - Betty Newcomb, 2002 (Box 4)
  - Town Bloody Hall, 2004, 5 folders (Box 4)
  - Massachusetts, 2004 (Box 4)
  - Connecticutt, 2005 (Box 4)
  - Helen Reddy, 2006 (Box 4)
  - Guests, 2006 May 1 (Box 4)
  - FWCA Barnard, 2006 Nov. (Box 4)
  - D.C. Area Pioneers, 2007 Oct. 30, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Fund letter, 1998 (Box 4)
  - Fund letter, 1999 (Box 4)
  - Donors, 1998-1999 (Box 4)
  - Donors, 1999-2000 (Box 4)
  - Fund letter, 2000 (Box 4)
  - Fund letter, 2001 (Box 4)
  - Fund letter, 2003, 3 folders (Box 4)
  - Fund returns, 2004 (Box 4)
  - MBRS, 2004 (Box 4)
  - Fund letter, 2005 (Box 4)
  - Original letters, 1990 (Box 4)
  - Artists (Box 4)
  - Azara (Box 4)
  - Helene Aylon (Box 4)
  - Susan Schwalb, Mass. (Box 4)
  - Suzanne Benton (Box 4)
  - Marilyn Cohen (Box 4)
  - Gloria Orenstein (Box 4)
  - Susan Faludi (Box 4)
  - Shulia Firestone (Box 4)
  - Marilyn Heins (Box 4)
  - Ann Forer (Box 4)
  - Estelle Freedman (Box 4)
  - Dan Horowitz (Box 4)
  - Joan Hull (Box 4)
  - Nan Johnson (Box 4)
  - Regina Litman (Box 4)
  - Robbi Madden (Box 5)
  - Susan Maurer (Box 5)
  - Kate Millett (Box 5)
  - Nesaule (Box 5)
  - Barbara Newall (Box 5)
  - Joyce Nower (Box 5)
  - Helen Pearl (Box 5)
  - Naomi Penner (Box 5)
  - Louise Raggio (Box 5)
  - Sandy Rapp (Box 5)
  - Trina Robbins (Box 5)
  - Kali Rost (Box 5)
  - Ruth Rosen (Box 5)
  - Doris Sassower (Box 5)
  - Kathy Sarachild (Box 5)
  - Charlotte Schwab (Box 5)
  - Arlie Scott (Box 5)
  - Sara Child (Box 5)
  - Lynne Shapiro (Box 5)
  - Elizabeth Shepard (Box 5)
  - Elayne Snyder (Box 5)
  - Virginia Artrip Snyder (Box 5)
  - Serena Italians (Box 5)
  - Ellie Smeal (Box 5)
  - Jane Sorluser (Box 5)
  - Maura Stark (Box 5)
  - Steinem (Box 5)
  - Charlene Suneson (Box 5)
  - Anne Sutherland Harris (Box 5)
  - Helen Thomas (Box 5)
  - Sheila Tobias (Box 5)
  - Joan Tobin (Box 5)
  - Anne Turpeau (Box 5)
  - Bede Urich (Box 5)
  - Mary Vasiliades (Box 5)
  - Winnie Wackwitz (Box 5)
  - Dennis Wainwright (Box 5)
  - Barbara G. Walker (Box 5)
  - Betsy Warrior (Box 5)
  - Sandy Warshaw (Box 5)
  - Virginia Watkins (Box 5)
  - Diane Watts (Box 5)
  - Grace Walch (Box 5)
  - Naomi Weisstein (Box 5)
  - Elaine Werner (Box 5)
  - Bonnie Wheeler (Box 5)
  - V. Whitehall (Box 5)
  - Dell Williams (Box 5)
  - Leslie Wolfe, Center for Women Policy Studies (Box 5)
  - Zalmar (Box 5)
  - Sandy Zwerling (Box 5)
  - Pioneer feminists: miscellaneous short bios (Box 5)
  - Biographies (Box 5)
  - Florida (Box 5)
  - Male feminists (Box 5)
  - National Women's Political Caucus (Box 5)
  - VFA Press releases (Box 5)
  - Publicity, VFA extras (Box 5)
  - Media (Box 5)
  - Feminist articles (Box 5)
  - Gallery books, 5 booklets (Box 5)
  - AWE, 2005 (Box 5)
  - Poets (Box 5)
  - June Blum: Portraits, Betty Friedan (Box 5)
  - NOW Legal Defense and Education Fund annual report, 2000 (Box 6)
  - NOW Conference, 2000 (Box 6)
  - Feminist Expo, 2000 (Box 6)
  - VFA Board, 2000 (Box 6)
  - 2000, 3 folders (Box 6)
  - Young feminists, 2000 (Box 6)
  - 2001 (Box 6)
  - Speakers Bureau, 2001 (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous, 2002 (Box 6)
  - Barbara Love, 2002 (Box 6)
  - 2002, 5 folders (Box 6)
  - Hall of Fame, 2003 (Box 6)
  - Michigan, 2003 (Box 6)
  - Emails, 2003 (Box 6)
  - Board and administrative files, 2003, 9 folders (Box 6)
  - Mass., 2004 (Box 6)
  - Emails, 2004 (Box 6)
  - Website, 2004 (Box 6)
  - Member mail (Box 6)
  - Midwest P.R., 2004 (Box 6)
  - Virgin Atlantic, 2004 (Box 6)
  - Dues, 2004 (Box 6)
  - Endowment (Box 6)
  - Administrative files, 2004, 10 folders (Box 6)
  - Author's salute, 2004 (Box 6)
  - Unfinished Business (Box 6)
  - Catherine East, 1993 (Box 7)
  - Flo Kennedy, 1993 Dec. (Box 7)
  - D.C., 1994 (Box 7)
  - Bella Abzug, 1994 (Box 7)
  - Marriage/Family, Spring 1995 (Box 7)
  - Gloria, Fall 1995 (Box 7)
  - 30th Anniversary of the Women's Movement, 1996 (Box 7)
  - Women's Liberation Movement, 1997 (Box 7)
  - Gerda Lerner, 1998 Apr. (Box 7)
  - Kate Millett, 1998 Nov. (Box 7)
  - Guests, 1999 (Box 7)
  - Chart, 1999 May (Box 7)
  - Program, 1999 May (Box 7)
  - Donna Allen, 1999 (Box 7)
  - Caroline Bird (Box 7)
  - Eliz. Boyer (Box 7)
  - June Chewning (Box 7)
  - Flora Crater (Box 7)
  - Allie Hixson (Box 7)
  - Tina Hobson (Box 7)
  - Marian Norby (Box 7)
  - Louise Raggio (Box 7)
  - Dusty Roads (Box 7)
  - Ruth Shinn (Box 7)
  - Carmen Delgado (Box 7)
  - Correspondence for 1999 May (Box 7)
  - Reunion, Spring 1999 (Box 7)
  - Honoring Betty Friedan, 1999 Nov., 9 folders (Box 7)
  - Catherine Adamsky, 2000 (Box 7)
  - Kathryn Avery (Box 7)
  - Ruth McLean Bowers (Box 7)
  - Evelyn Dubrow (Box 7)
  - Minnette Doderer (Box 7)
  - Arienne Fraser (Box 7)
  - Vera Glaser (Box 7)
  - Dorothy Haegele (Box 7)
  - Stephanie Gilmore (Box 7)
  - Strike, 1970 (30th Anniversary), 3 folders (Box 7)
  - Louisiana Pioneer Feminists March, 2001, 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Women's Studies, 2001 June (Box 7)
  - Feminist Florida, 2002 (Box 7)
  - Dinner with Isadora, 2002 (Box 7)
  - Title IX 30th Anniversary, 2002 (Box 7)
  - Isadora report (Box 7)
  - Art event, 2003, 9 folders (Box 7)
  - History of abortion in the USA (Box 8)
  - VFA writings (Box 8)
  - VFA, 1993 (Box 8)
  - Battered women (Box 8)
  - By interest and profession (Box 8)
  - Intergenerational (Box 8)
  - The F word, 2004 (Box 8)
  - 3rd wave feminism, 2002 (Box 8)
  - Dads and daughters (Box 8)
  - Foam mounted copies of book covers, 5 covers (Box 8)
  - Biographies for Barbara Love book, A-K (Box 8)
  - Biographies for Barbara Love book, L-R (Box 9)
  - Foam mounted copies of book covers, 13 covers (Box 9)
  - Obituaries, A-R, 63 folders (Box 9)
  - Obituaries, R-Z, 16 folders (Box 10)
  - 1990-1997, 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Videos, 1993-2000, 3 folders (Box 10)
  - NOW 30th, 1996 (Box 10)
  - Betty Friedan event, 1999 (Box 10)
  - Renewals, 1994-1995 (Box 10)
  - Future honorees (Box 10)
  - Biographies, radical women, 1997 (Box 10)
  - Information sent, 1994 (Box 10)
  - Unfoldered material (Box 10)
  - Anti-Defamation League, 2000 (Box 10)
  - Texas, members and prospective, 1993-1996 (Box 10)
  - Women Leaders Online Summit, 1999 (Box 10)
  - Kim Gandy, 1991 (Box 10)
  - Letter to VFW Board, 1992 (Box 10)
  - Wonderful 1st letters (Box 10)
  - Correspondence, 1992-1996, 8 folders (Box 10)
  - NOW Resolution re: VFA, 1996 (Box 10)
  - Tickets, 1993-2000, 10 envelopes (Box 11)
  - Articles/projects (Box 11)
  - Books (Box 11)
  - 1998 Event (Box 11)
  - FWCA, Barbara's book (Box 11)
  - Women's Liberation Event, 1997 (Box 11)
  - Mother Daughter Revolution (Box 11)
  - Biographies, photographs (Box 11)
  - Publications (Box 11)
  - Binder: Female Studies, 1970 (Box 11)
  - Binder: Feminist Educators Attending Dinner, 2001 (Box 11)
  - Binder: 1994 (Box 11)
  - Binder: Catherine East, 1993 (Box 11)
  - World March, 2000 (Box 11)
  - West Coast Reunion (Box 11)
  - NOW 30th, 1996 (Box 11)
  - Marriage/Divorce (Box 11)
  - Seneca Falls, 75th Suffrage (Box 11)
  - Grant, 1996 (Box 12)
  - Correspondence, 1996-1998, 3 folders (Box 12)
  - Applications, 1995-1998 (Box 12)
  - Correspondence, 1998, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Celebrate, 1998 (Box 12)
  - Step by Step, 1999 (Box 12)
  - Administrative, funding, program files, 1996-1999, 15 folders (Box 12)
  - Letter to Betty Friedan, 2000 (Box 12)
  - Dues/Contributions, 2000 (Box 12)
  - Barnard Conference, 2001 June, 9 folders (Box 12)
  - Florida NOW Conference, 2002 (Box 12)
  - Artists, 2003, 3 folders (Box 12)
  - Boston event, 2007 (Box 13)
  - Emails, 2007, 4 folders (Box 13)
  - Dues, 2007 (Box 13)
  - Webpage, 2007, 2 folders (Box 13)
  - Artists, 2007 (Box 13)
  - Fund letter, 2007 (Box 13)
  - Smith Barney VFA, 2007 (Box 13)
  - Phoenix event, 2007 (Box 13)
  - New members, 2007 (Box 13)
  - E-Newsletters, 2007 (Box 13)
  - California events, Feminists Who Changed America (Box 13)
  - Bella, Houston, 2007 (Box 13)
  - D.C. and New York City, 2007 (Box 13)
  - NOW Conference, 2007 (Box 13)
  - Letters, emails, etc., 2000-2006 (Box 13)
  - Women make movies (Box 13)
  - Boca event, 2007 (Box 13)
  - ERA news (Box 13)
  - National Women's Hall of Fame, 2 folders (Box 13)
  - Cartoons (Box 13)
  - T shirts, medal, 1993 (Box 13)
  - Biographies, 1970 group (Box 13)
  - Patricia Hill Burnett, 2002 (Box 13)
  - Newcomb's invitation, 2001 (Box 13)
  - NWSA Conference, 2003 (Box 13)
  - Women's Rights Park, 1999 (Box 13)
  - New members, 2003-2004, 2 folders (Box 13)
  - Invitations (copies) (Box 13)
  - Future newsletters (Box 13)
  - Files by State, C-K (Box 13)
  - Files by State, L-W (Box 14)
  - Catherine East, 1993 (Box 14)
  - Dennis Wainstock interview, 2002 (Box 14)
  - Loose materials (Box 14)
  - Women's Studies, 2001 (Box 14)
  - Biographies, writers (Box 14)
  - LDEF (Box 14)
  - Newsletters (Box 14)
  - Periodicals, 1977-2006, 3 folders (Box 14)
  - VHS cassettes, 6 tapes (Box 14)
  - Women-owned businesses (Box 14)
  - Jewish feminists (Box 14)
  - Grey Panthers (Box 14)
  - Michigan, 1998 (Box 14)
  - Binder: Bella Abzug event, 1994 (Box 14)
  - Binder: Gloria Steinem event, 1995 (Box 14)
  - Binder: Women's Liberation 30th Anniversary, 1997, 2 folders (Box 15)
  - Binder: Ruth Loyd Miller (Box 15)
  - Binder: NOW 30th, 1996, 2 folders (Box 15)
  - Photographs (Box 15)
  - Photographs in envelopes
    - Expo, Baltimore, 2000 (Box 15)
    - NOW Conference, Miami, 2000 (Box 15)
    - California, 2002, 2 envelopes (Box 15)
    - L.A., 2002 (Box 15)
    - St. Paul, 2002 (Box 15)
    - NOW Conference, Florida, 2002 (Box 15)
    - Connecticutt, 2005 (Box 15)
    - Photos of demonstrations, send by Lee Perkins, Virginia (Box 15)
    - New Orleans, 2001 (Box 15)
    - Women's Studies, Barnard, 2001 (Box 15)
    - Catherine, 1993, 2 folders (Box 15)
    - Boca Raton, 2002 (Box 15)
    - Writers, Barnard, 2002 (Box 15)
    - Baltimore, 2002 (Box 15)
    - Art Event, 2003 (Box 15)
    - Newton, Mass., 2004 (Box 15)
    - Chicago, 2004-2005, 2 envelopes (Box 15)
    - San Diego, 2002 (Box 15)
    - Berkeley, 2002 (Box 15)
    - Pro-Choice March, D.C., 1992, 4 albums (Box 15)
    - April 1998 (Box 15)
    - Kate, 1998 (Box 15)
    - D.C., 1994 (Box 15)
    - Bella, 1994 (Box 15)
    - Marriage and Divorce, Irvington, NY, 1995 (Box 15)
    - NOW reunion, 1996 (Box 15)
    - Cocktail Party, 1994 (Box 15)
    - VFA Reunion, 2002 (Box 15)
    - San Francisco, 1999 (Box 15)
    - August 1999 (Box 15)
    - Betty event, 1999, 3 envelopes (Box 15)
  - VHS cassettes, 3 tapes (Box 15)
  - Bag of political campaign buttons (Box 15)
  - Bag of VFA medals and pins (Box 15)
  - Miscellaneous papers (Box 16)
  - Broward (Box 16)
  - Barbara Foreman Scott (Box 16)
  - Gene: Organizing as a Business (Box 16)
  - Posters, photos (Box 16)
  - Photos New Orleans, 2001 (Box 16)
  - Elizabeth Sackler (Box 16)
  - Bylaws, 1997-1999 (Box 16)
  - Copyright VFA (Box 16)
  - Miscellanous files, 5 folders (Box 16)
  - Binder: VFA Photographs Kate, 1990-1999, 2 folders (Box 16)
  - Katrina help, 2005 (Box 16)
  - Women Make Movies catalog, 2002 (Box 16)
  - Forum 1998 (Box 16)
  - ERA, 2004-2005 (Box 16)
  - African American feminists (Box 16)
  - California Women's Agenda, 1997 (Box 16)
  - Miscellaneous materials (Box 16)
  - Louisiana (Box 16)
  - Miscellaneous materials (Box 16)
  - Periodicals, 3 folders (Box 16)
  - Periodicals (Box 17)
  - National Women's History Project (Box 17)
  - Unfinished Business (Box 17)
  - Photo album of Ida Martinez (Box 17)
  - Photographs, 7 envelopes (Box 17)
  - DVDs
    - VFA Part Two, 2005 (Box 17)
    - Passing the Torch: The Women's Movement in Michigan, 2006 (Box 17)
    - Women Now and Yes Baby, She's My Sir, 2008 (Box 17)
  - San Diego Feminists photo album and autographs, 2002 (Box 18)
  - World March of Women poster, 2000 (Box 18)
  - Foam posters, 2 items (Box 18)
- Accession (2008-0254), 1993-2008; 2 boxes
  The addition (2008-0254) (64 items; 1.2 lin. ft.) consists of DVDs of VFA events and interviews. For more detailed information about the events and activities, please see the donor-generated descriptions housed in the Collection Control File.
  - Salute to Catherine East, 1993 (Box 19)
  - Salute to Pioneer Feminists, 1994 (Box 19)
  - Salute to Family Justice Lawyers, Judges, and Activists, 1995 (Box 19)
  - Two-Day Celebration of NOW 30th Anniversary, 1996, 3 DVDs (Box 19)
  - Thirtieth Anniversary of Women's Liberation, 1997, 2 DVDs (Box 19)
  - Honors Dinner, 1998, 2 DVDs (Box 19)
  - Salute to Kate Millett, 1998, 2 DVDs (Box 19)
  - Salute to ERA Activists and Other Major Leaders, 1999, 2 DVDs (Box 19)
  - Salute to Betty Friedan, 1999, 2 DVDs (Box 19)
  - Thirtieth Anniversary of Aug. 26, 1970 Strike for Equality, 2000, 2 DVDs (Box 19)
  - Salute to Feminist Educators and Women's Studies Founders, 2001, 2 DVDs (Box 19)
  - Honoring Florida Feminists, 2002 (Box 19)
  - Salute to Feminist Writers, 2002, 3 DVDs (Box 19)
  - Honoring Those Who Made Title IX Happen, 2002, 4 DVDs (Box 19)
  - Salute to Feminists in the Arts, 2003, 2 of 4 DVDs (Box 19)
  - Salute to Feminists in the Arts, 2003, 2 of 4 DVDs (Box 20)
  - Equal Pay and Job Opportunities: A Conference Celebrating 40 Years of Title VII, 2004, 9 DVDs (Box 20)
  - Unfinished Business of the Women's Movement: Conference and Dinner Honoring Midwest Feminists, 2004, 5 DVDs (Box 20)
  - Feminism and its Values, an Intergenerational Dialogue, 2005, 2 DVDs (Box 20)
  - Honoring Helen Reddy, 2006 (Box 20)
  - Awards Dinner for Los Angeles Feminists, 2006, 4 DVDs (Box 20)
  - Publication Debut of Feminists Who Changed America, 1963-1975, 2006, 7 DVDs (Box 20)
  - Salute to Arizona Feminists, 2007, not shipped because of poor DVD quality (Box 20)
  - Salute to Arizona Feminists II, 2007, 2 DVDs (Box 20)
  - Salute to Feminist Lawyers, 2008, 3 DVDs, to arrive late 2008 (Box 20)
- Accession (2009-0131), 2001-2008; 2 boxes
  The addition (2009-0131) (900 items; 1.2 lin. ft., dated 2001-2008) consists of board minutes, administrative materials, program files, some correspondence, and publicity. Program files include reunions, special presentations, conferences on feminist history and issues, and other educational and commemorative events. In particular, this accession includes materials from the VFA Salute to Feminist Lawyers program held in June 2008.
  - Board minutes and files, 2003-2008 (Box 21)
  - Administrative files, 2002-2006
    - Voting policies (Box 21)
    - Reports (Box 21)